人人影视倾情奉献
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   苏小黛
翻译   吃冰棒
翻译   草草
翻译   Lynn_宁
时间轴   壬虚浪影
时间轴   纸袋P
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第五季  第九集
安德伍德拿下俄亥俄
康威将认输
将军竟然说要杀死总统
The general talked about killing the president.
再加上康威在飞机上的爆发
That, along with Conway's outburst on the plane--
这么说好像夸大了实际情况
That sounds worse than it was.
不  实际情况就是这么严重
No, that sounds exactly as bad as it was.
让我觉得惊讶的是
What's surprising to me is...
选举团队竟然应对不过来
the campaign couldn't get their hands around this.
哈里·马歇尔已经很厉害了
I mean, Harry Marshall is as good as they come, but--
他们先是否认  接着又模棱两可
First they denied, and then they equivocated--
这简直太荒唐了
I mean, that's just, like, ridiculous.
你站出来
You just come out,
"我道歉  我们说错话了"
"I apologize. We misspoke."
所有人都知道这套路
Everybody knows the drill here.
共和党人也没有冲过去帮他们
And it's not like the Republicans rushed in
力挽狂澜
to save the day either.
-完全不谈正题  -他们默不作声
- Off message throughout. - They got quiet.
这一点我怎么也想不通
Which I will never understand.
威尔·康威可是党内冉冉升起的新星
Will Conway was a rising star in the party.
怎么能跟安德伍德政治机器相匹敌呢
Look, it's hard to compete with the Underwood machine.
天啊  我们别再说这些"阴谋占领"的疯话了
God. Let's not do the whole "black helicopters" crazy stuff.
太荒唐了
It's ridiculous.
我们得接受安德伍德赢得大选这一事实
Look, we need to accept Underwood won the election.
公众得接受这个结果  继续前进
People need to accept the outcome and move on.
我同意范的观点
I'm gonna agree with Van.
我觉得我们应该感激宪法
I think we need to take a moment to appreciate the Constitution.
它会弯折[妥协]It bent,
-但不会折断[毁坏]  -说得没错
- but it never broke. - That's right.
我们都知道  到最后
And in the end, as we all know,
还是由选举人团决定
it came down to the Electoral College.
你不用说那句话  州长
You don't have to say the words, Governor.
我应该说
I think I do.
恭喜  当选总统先生
Congratulations, Mr. President Elect.
这次没有稿子吗
There's no script for this one?
国家第一  先生
Country first, sir.
我很高兴你这么说  威尔
I'm glad to hear you say that, Will.
我想帮这个国家愈合
I want to start to help the country heal again.
说完了吗
Are we done?
说完了  但是威尔
We are done. But Will...
我很想向国家展示
I would very much like to show the country
我们两党可以齐心协作
that our two parties can work together.
我希望你考虑
So I was hoping that you might consider
做我的运输部长
becoming my transportation secretary.
如果你同意加入我的内阁
I think it would send a powerful message
会发出一个强有力的信号
if you agreed to join my cabinet.
你觉得我能
You think I'd...
当好运输部长吗
make a good... transportation secretary?
没错
Yes.
这是开给无名议员的条件
That's what you give the congressman from nowhere.
我会拒绝的
I'll be declining.
听到你这么说真是太遗憾了  威尔
Well, I'm so sorry to hear that, Will.
我想祝你一切顺利
And I wanted to wish you the very best.
去你的  去你的祝福
You and your wishes can go fuck yourselves!
我现在做什么
What do I do now?
所有人都以为威尔会赢
...everyone thought it would happen.
没人想到安德伍德还能赢
No one thought that Underwood would win again...
我不知道
I don't know.
承认失败从来都不容易
Acknowledging defeat is never easy.
在公众面前承认更是无比煎熬
Doing it in public is a living hell.
起码媒体喜欢他
Well, at least the cameras like him.
我看着满意吗
Do I look satisfied?
你看着还算满意
You look somewhat satisfied.
-好  -"好"可不够
- Good. - Not good.
弗兰西斯  享受这一刻吧
Francis, enjoy this moment.
-这是你应得的  -是"我们"吧
- You deserve it. - You mean "we."
我们成功到达另一边了
We made it to the other side.
是啊
Yes.
但另一边有什么
But what is on the other side?
胜利
Victory.
稍带点失败的气息
With a whiff of defeat.
花了好久才走到这一步
It's taken a long time to get here,
但我们到了
but we're here.
干杯  弗兰西斯
Cheers, Francis.
今后一切都会变得容易
Everything gets easier from now on.
他们准备好了
They're ready for you.
-汉娜  -我不想去
- Hannah. - I don't want to go.
不
No.
好吧
Fine.
那我自己去吧
I'll do it on my own.
要知道  这是个重要时刻
I'm gonna say, this is a crucial moment.
对你们两个都是
For both of you.
看你们如何应对
How you handle tonight.
党抛弃了我
The party abandoned me.
你的党
Your party.
我不是共和党  威尔
I'm not the Republican Party, Will.
我只为候选人效力
I work for candidates.
我为你效力
I worked for you.
听好  你输了
Listen, you lost.
但还有一多半国民
But more than half the country
仍认为你是他们的总统
still considers you their president.
你必须要面对他们
This is what's required.
走出去  发表讲话
Go down there, give your speech.
认输吧
Concede.
国务卿  华盛顿
尊敬的总统先生
我谨辞去第68任国务卿职务
此致
凯瑟琳·杜兰特
我正式接受各位的辞呈
As I accept all of your letters of resignation
并解散我的旧内阁
and dissolve my old cabinet,
然后我想欢迎在座各位加入我的新内阁
I wanna welcome each and every one of you to my new cabinet.
-恭喜你  总统先生  -谢谢  凯茜
- Congratulations, Mr. President. - Thank you, Cathy.
我尤其想感谢我的妻子
And I especially wanna thank my wife.
副总统女士
Madam Vice President...
感谢你对我长期坚定的支持
thank you for your unending and unwavering support.
这一个月来  你的坚强领导维持了国家的运作
Your steady hand kept this country running this past month.
我欠她太多  多到我无法想象
I owe her more than I can possibly fathom.
而她也欠我
And she owes me.
不对  你一直在我身边支持着我
Not true. You were with me all the way.
作为合法当选总统
I would like to make my first 100 days
我希望我的头一百天能取得尽可能多的成绩
as the duly elected president as productive as possible.
当然  挑战还是很多的
Of course, there are many challenges.
提振经济
Shoring up the economy,
保护我国不受哈里发国攻击
securing our nation from ICO
还要降低失业率
and reducing unemployment.
但我们面对的最艰巨的问题
But the biggest challenge that we face,
也是我最需要各位通力协助的挑战
and the one that I'm going to need all of your help on,
就是重新团结全国
is reuniting a country
弥合这个国家前所未有的裂痕
that has never been more divided than it is today.
我相信我们可以迎难而上
I believe we can meet this challenge,
而我需要各位的帮助
and that's where I'm gonna need all of your help.
所以今天我们就开始治愈国家
So let's let the healing begin today
共同创造历史吧
and let's make history together.
感谢你们长久的辛勤奉献
I thank you all for your continued service.
现在回去工作吧
Now let's get back to work.
我需要一分钟
I need a minute.
我想我们应该早做打算
I think we should see what we can do
把厄舍赶走
about making Usher persona non grata.
现在开战不合适吧
I don't think that's wise to start a war.
我们才刚刚拿下白宫
We've just won the White House.
现在才是出手的最佳时机
This is exactly when we should strike.
只有现在我们才有足够的政治资本
This is a moment that we have the political capital...
厄舍必须小心处理
Usher needs to be managed carefully.
总统先生
Mr. President?
喘口气吧  道格
Take a breath, Doug.
我们才刚刚站稳脚跟
We've only just landed on our feet here.
先生  副总统女士
Sir, Madam Vice President,
过去在众议院  这种人就是重点打击对象
this is the type of person that we used to crucify in the House.
但现在我们不在众议院  我们在白宫
Yes, but we're not in the House now. We're here.
我们还有一整个任期呢
We have a full term ahead of us.
我们肯定会取得
There's gonna be a great deal
非常多的成就
that we're gonna be able to accomplish,
咱们三个合作
the three of us.
感谢您的器重  先生
I appreciate that, sir.
但是马克·厄舍早晚会变成麻烦的
But Mark Usher will become a problem.
每个人早晚都会变成麻烦
Well, everyone becomes a problem, eventually.
莉安出局了
LeAnn's out.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
她搞砸了
She screwed up.
有什么需要我准备的吗
Well, is it something I need to get ready for?
安德伍德夫妇希望间接处理她
The Underwoods want this handled indirectly.
所以我们具体该说什么
So what exactly are we saying?
她被赶走了
She's being pushed out.
好  但是选举结束了
Okay, but the campaign's over.
还有必要对外说什么吗
Is it necessary to say anything?
我们需要撇清本届政府与她
We need to distance this administration
和她工作的关系
from her and her work.
还有她的策略
Her tactics.
得装成是泄露出去的
So it needs to be a leak.
泄露给不喜欢我们的人
Reach out to the people who don't like us.
他们肯定乐意爆料
They'll be prime to go with it.
等我们回应的时候
Okay, so when we respond...
-是公开还是  -公开
- On the record or... - On.
她做了什么
What did she do?
她展现出了很差的判断力
She showed some very poor judgment.
我相信你会谨慎的
I'm trusting you to be discreet.
我们赢了  赛斯
We won, Seth.
需要做出一些改变
Changes need to be made.
你知道我已经远离政治了
You know I'm off politics.
你来找我  我真的很惊讶
Surprised you reached out to me.
你是一位非常受人尊敬的记者
You're a highly-respected journalist.
就是来参加就职典礼和舞会而已
Just here for the inauguration and the parties.
我想你已经听说了  我被赶走了
So I imagine you've heard that I'm on the outs.
他们没有说出全部实情
They're not telling the whole story.
发生了什么
So what happened?
我有个熟人
An acquaintance of mine
从国安局偷了机密文件
stole classified documents from the NSA
去了俄罗斯
and took off to Russia.
他们因为这件事责怪我
They're blaming me for it.
你这个熟人带走的是什么
What did this acquaintance take?
问题就是这个  我也不知道
That's just the thing. I have no idea.
要是你能找到他  跟他谈谈
If you could find him, talk to him,
他会告诉你  我和这事一点关系都没有
he would tell you that I had nothing to do with this.
他是谁  他叫什么
Who is he? What's his name?
艾丹·麦卡伦
Aidan Macallan.
他会跟你谈的  他尊重你
He'll talk to you. He respects you.
告诉他我现在没事
Tell him that I'm okay.
以后也会没事的
That I'm going to be okay.
我坚信派遣地面部队
I'm a firm believer in boots on the ground.
我们就是为了石油去的  别装了
Well, we're there for the oil. Let's not pretend.
我不否认保护原油供应的重要性
I'm not denying how crucial it is to protect the oil supply.
但由我们来盯住
But it's in the world's best interest
对整个世界都好
that we're the ones keeping an eye on it.
-盯住世界还是石油  -都是
- On the world or the oil? - Both.
难怪你对南极那么感兴趣
Well, that explains your strong interest in Antarctica.
我确实关注事情和人
I do focus on things and people.
我常会起怜惜之情
I tend to get attached,
但我觉得这让我的工作更加出色
but I think it makes me better at what I do.
你现在关注什么
And what are you focused on now?
首先是佩特罗夫和艾哈迈德·艾哈迈迪
Petrov. Ahmed Al Ahmadi. To begin with.
抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
我只是
I just...
我明天再问你的意见
I'll run this by you tomorrow.
好  明天
Yes, tomorrow.
抱歉打断你们了
Sorry for the interruption.
他是我们的一个演讲撰稿人
He's one of our speechwriters.
汤姆·耶茨很有名
Tom Yates has quite a reputation.
要是他的书能说明什么的话
Well, if his books are any indication,
他的生活可很精彩
he has lived quite a life.
我爸爸也穿条纹袜
My father wore striped socks.
你觉得总统会赞同我们的议程吗
Do you think the president will be sympathetic to our agenda?
"我们的议程"  这么说太自负了
"Our agenda"? That's very presumptuous.
这世界上有些地区
Well, there are regions in the world
对我们的国家安全很重要
that are important to our national security
我们必须保护这些地区
and they have to be protected.
你想跟我们一起参加就职舞会吗
Would you like to join us at the inaugural ball?
不行
Oh, no, I can't.
只要我去舞会  就会发生可怕的事
Something terrible always happens when I go to a party.
顺说  我丈夫不会受任何人的摆布
By the way, my husband is not managed by anyone.
-我不是这个意思  -不是吗
- That's not what I'm asking. - Isn't it?
我是想让你帮忙  副总统女士
I'm asking for your help, Madam Vice President.
仅此而已
That is all.
晚上好
Evening.
天啊  进来吧
Oh, my God. Come in.
抱歉  坐吧  坐吧
I'm sorry. Sit down, sit down.
今晚不锻炼了吗
Aren't we working out tonight?
我应该是没时间了
I just don't think I'm gonna have the time for it.
过来坐一会儿
But come sit for a minute.
要是你太忙的话
If you're too busy,
-我能理解  -不  来跟我坐会儿
- I understand-- - No, no. Join me for a minute.
我想让你听点东西
I want you to hear something.
"这是新时代的黎明
"This is the dawn of a new era.
这是和平的时代
It's a time for peace.
要尊重过去  拥抱未来
A time to respect the past and embrace the future.
要..."
A time..."
要什么
Time to what?
"要聆听所有声音
"A time to hear all the voices.
因为世间最大的孤独
For there is nothing more lonely...
恐怖
or terrifying...
便是无人聆听"
than feeling unheard."
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
有意思  我喜欢
It's interesting. I like it.
-这是为了  -我的就职典礼  没错
- This is for... - My inauguration, yes.
然后呢  你接下去怎么说
Where does it go from there? What do you say?
"美国人民  我听到了你们的声音
"America, I hear you.
无论你们是否投票给了我
Whether you voted for me or not,
我听到了你们所有人的声音"
I hear all of you."
你觉得我的曾曾曾祖父
Now, what do you think my great-great-great-grandfather
会怎么评价这些
would think of all this?
令人敬畏[非常好]
Awesome.
-就这词原本的意思  -是啊
- In the original sense of the word. - Yeah.
你要在这儿待多久
How long you in town for?
实际上  今晚就走
Leaving tonight, actually.
我以为你是来参加就职典礼的
I thought you were here for the inauguration.
我收到了一条消息  得走了
I got a tip I have to move on.
什么消息
What's the tip?
咱们以前对工作谈话可是有规矩的
We used to have a rule about shoptalk.
是吗
Did we?
好吧
Fair enough.
你怎么看莉安·哈维
What's your read on LeAnn Harvey?
她很难看透  这也是我喜欢她之处
That she's hard to read. That's what I like about her.
你信任她
You trust her?
凯特  拜托
Kate, come on.
你很憔悴
You look tired.
我现在一周工作八天
I'm working eight days a week.
你以前也总是很憔悴的样子
I mean, you always looked tired,
但你现在的憔悴  不那么性感了
but now you look tired in a... not sexy way.
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint.
其实我马上就得回去了
I actually have to get back there in a minute.
这会儿回办公室有点晚了吧
It's little late to head back to the office, right?
我从上周二起就一直在那边
I've been there since last Tuesday.
说实话
Honestly...
我知道这话听起来有点怪
I know this sounds weird...
但我没有更想去的地方了
There's no place I'd rather be.
你这话的语气真...生硬
The way you say that sounds so... rote.
我说不好
I don't know...
这让我怎么回应
What am I supposed to say to that?
我只想知道你好不好  仅此而已
I just want to know how you're doing, that's all.
我只是关心你  坐在我眼前的这个人
I'm just asking about you, this person I'm sitting with.
你想什么呢  汤姆·耶茨
Where'd you go, Tom Yates?
我找你来着
I was looking for you.
看来找得不够用心啊
Not very hard, then.
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
好
Okay.
我不干了
I'm done.
我不想再写演讲稿了
With the speechwriting, I don't want to do it anymore.
我想回去做我之前在做的其他事
I want to get back to some other stuff I was working on.
没别的意思  我知道写演讲稿也是写作
No offense. I mean, I know writing speeches is writing...
但这不是我真正想做的
but it's not what I really wanna do.
好
Okay.
你确定
You sure?
是的
Yes.
我们会把你调出去的
We'll transition you out.
但你以后再来就得想好借口了
But you'll need to have a reason to be here.
马克·厄舍被任命为总统特别顾问
特别顾问  你逗我吗
Special advisor? Are you kidding me?
有猜测说他已经...
There's speculation that he's already...
这不是猜测  赛斯
It's not speculation, Seth.
人们知道马克·厄舍在某种程度上为我们工作
People know that Mark Usher is working for us in some capacity.
-那还不够吗  -把发布写得好一点
- I mean, isn't that enough? - Clean up this release.
突破党派界限之类的
Uh, reaching across party lines, that sort of thing.
-准备好  以防万一  -当然
- And get it ready, just in case. - Of course.
就这样
That's it.
我知道你不高兴
I know you're not happy about this.
他凭什么能赢得那头衔
What has he done to earn the title?
这不是他赢得什么的问题
This is not about him earning anything.
他已经在接触机密备忘录了
He's already getting classified memos.
她为什么想这样
Why does she want this?
"她"
"She"?
抱歉  我是说副总统
I'm sorry. The vice president.
她想要的是让这个政府成功
What she wants is for this administration to succeed.
而我想要的是你跟他成为朋友  了解他
And what I want is for you to befriend him. Get to know him.
我们要让他以为是他在操控我们
We want him to think he's managing us
而其实是我们在控制他
while we're busy managing him.
她追查弗兰西斯·安德伍德很久了
She has been pursuing Francis Underwood for a long time.
-我不想和她谈  -艾丹
- I don't wanna talk to her. - Aidan...
她怎么知道我在这儿的
How does she even know I'm here?
鲍德温女士是个非常优秀的记者
Miss Baldwin is a very good journalist.
把事情公开对你和我都没帮助
Yeah, going public will not help you, or me.
你就跟她说说  你是怎么操纵美国民意的
You'll tell her how you manipulated the American mood, hmm?
-你是怎么偷走大选胜利的  -那我就完了
- How you helped steal an election. - That would be it for me.
你可是我们俄罗斯联邦的贵客
You're a valued guest of the Russian state.
我想要回我的护照
I want my passport back.
美国护照是绝对保护不了你的
An American passport is the last thing that will keep you safe.
我愿赌一把
I'll take my chances.
这下你要出名了  当个告密者
This will make you famous, hmm? A whistle-blower.
我不想出名
I don't wanna be famous.
但你想要自由
But you do want to be free.
传票
由美国国会众议院签发
致  尊敬的泰伦斯·乌麦克
现传召您来众议院纪律委员会出席听证
日程安排
你光饭钱就花了一万五
You spent $15,000 at The Capital Grille?
你吃金子吗
What the fuck are you eating?
-这是罗梅洛利用纪律委员会  -这是把柄
- This is Romero using the House Ethics... - It's a liability.
你就不该犯这种错
And you should know better.
这事你怎么没说过  泰瑞
How did you not disclose this, Terry?
我想把他踢出委员会
I want to pull him off his committee assignments.
扔进科学委员会  看他喜不喜欢宇航局报告
Put him on Science. See how he likes NASA briefings.
先缓缓吧
I'd like to hold off on that.
罗梅洛就要成为总统的亲密盟友了
Romero's about to become an ally to the president.
怎么会呢
And why's that?
因为他能查出你的账单有问题
Because he was able to find out about your tab.
因为他从不轻易放手
It's because he's relentless.
因为四年后亚利桑那州35%的选民是拉丁裔
Because in four years, 35% of the vote in Arizona will be Latino.
因为他就是未来
Because he's the future.
就是这么开始的
This is how it starts.
我得回国会去了
I gotta get back to the Hill.
跟你说  道格
You know, Doug...
你我都待得够久  见过换护卫
you and I, we've been around long enough to see the guard change.
之所以会换人  是因为上头那些人
And it changes because the people at the top
忘了自己是怎么爬上去的
forget how they got there.
罗梅洛也想换护卫  道格
Romero's trying to change the guard, Doug.
而我们就是护卫
And we are the guard.
要是乌麦克议员无所隐瞒
If Congressman Womack has nothing to hide,
那他就没什么好怕的
he has nothing to fear.
我们都有要隐瞒的事  罗梅洛议员
We all have something to hide, Congressman Romero.
领导层该换人了
It's time for a change in the leadership.
总统想当你的朋友
The president would like to be a friend to you,
但你让他很难做
but you're making it very difficult.
我们可以保证移民禁令
We can guarantee the immigration ban
下星期就会取消
will be lifted in the next week.
拜托  又来这一套吗
Come on. Are we doing this again?
你开个种族歧视的条件
You offer me some racist gesture.
我怎么  就当死党吗  本来你也禁不住
And I, what? I'm a friend forever? Ban isn't even sustainable.
你最在乎的究竟是什么
What matters to you?
-总统的注意力  -你有啊
- The president's attention. - You have it.
-全部的注意力  -你过分了
- His full attention... - You know, that's enough.
你到底想要什么
What is it that you really want?
我想要医保覆盖率调回原来的水平
I want Medicare coverage bumped up to where it was.
我的选区有不少退休工人
There are retirees in my district.
你见我就只想要扩大医保吗
We're here now because you want a bump in Medicare?
得了吧  议员
Come on, Congressman.
还有两个就职典礼的座位
And two seats to the inauguration.
-就剩两天了  -讲台座位
- We are two days out. - On the dais.
你的算盘完全打错了
You are going about this entirely wrong.
是你主动来找我  是你求我
You came here. You asked me.
我告诉你
I'm telling you.
我就想看弗兰西斯·安德伍德当着我的面
I want to be there when Francis Underwood says to me
宣布提高医保水平
that there will be an increase in Medicare.
只要他一句话  我就是他铁哥们
He does that, I'm his friend.
那我现在就可以代表总统
Well, I think I speak for the president
告诉你这事根本不可能
when I say that's not going to happen.
斯坦普先生  我真的很钦佩你为他做的一切
Mr. Stamper, I really appreciate all the work you do for him,
但你我都知道我的党团在扩大
but you and I know that my bloc is growing.
我只要求他在就职讲话里说句话
All I'm looking for is a line in his address.
两个座位  一句话
Two seats and a line.
-好大的胆子  -我告诉他基本没可能
- The balls on him. - I told him it was highly doubtful.
我可以再回去正式拒绝他
I can get back to him with a firm no.
或者你可以答应他提一句
Or you could give him a line.
他的保证很不可靠
His promises are unreliable.
我了解艾力克斯  我们在康威竞选时见过面
Look, I know Alex. We met on Conway's campaign.
只要他加入  就一定死心塌地
Once he's in, he's in.
总统先生  我们得谨慎决定要给出什么条件
Sir, we have to be very careful with what we're giving away.
他能给政府带来
He's capable of giving this administration
巨大的困扰
an enormous amount of grief.
他只是想让我们对他示好
He's asking for a gesture.
要我说可不止
Oh, I'd say it's a little more than that.
完全同意  他想找帮我们获胜的人的麻烦
I completely agree. He's going after the people who got us here.
他并没有错  对吗
He's not wrong, is he?
有些领导层的人确实该下台了
There are some in leadership whose time has come and gone.
瞧  我是来确保
Look... I'm just here to make sure
你能连任的
your four years turn into eight, but...
但决定权还是在你手上
it's up to you, of course.
他要的不过是两个座位  一句话
But we're talking about two seats... one line...
答应他的要求
Give him what he wants.
艾力克斯
Alex.
蒂尔达  很高兴见到你
Tilda. It's lovely to see you.
-你好吗  议员  -挺好的
- How are you, Congressman? - Oh, I'm fine.
很高兴你们都来了  今天是个大日子
It's good of you all to be here. It's a big day.
要不你们坐我的位子
Listen, why don't the two of you take my seats?
谢了  我们已经被安排在走道旁了
Oh, thanks, but we're already on the aisle.
你们务必收下
I insist.
这样总统说到你想听的话时
You'll be right in the president's line of vision when he...
你正好能与他对视
says what you want to hear.
请吧  我在哪都行
Please. I can be anywhere.
好吧
Okay.
-谢谢你  马克  -别客气
- Thank you, Mark. - Sure.
弗兰西斯·安德伍德就职典礼
我  弗兰西斯·安德伍德  庄严宣誓
I, Francis J. Underwood, do solemnly swear...
我必忠实执行...
That I will faithfully execute...
合众国总统职务
The office of President of the United States.
合众国总统...是的  这一幕似曾相识
The office of Pres-- Yes, here we go again.
国务卿  那时我是想要这个位子
Secretary of State. That's what I wanted.
我只想要这个位子  也是当时许诺给我的
That's all I wanted. That's what I was promised.
而现在  瞧瞧我
And now, here I am,
成了美国总统
President of these United States.
美国人民  这是你们促成的
You made this bed, America.
是你们投票给我的
You voted for me.
困惑吗
Are you confused?
害怕吗
Are you afraid?
因为你以为的梦想成真了
Because what you thought you wanted is now here.
现在你在看着我
And there you are, staring back,
目瞪口呆  一头雾水
slack-jawed, bewildered,
心想这究竟是不是你们想要的
wondering if this is what you actually asked for.
是民主  你们的民主选择了我
This democracy, your democracy, elected me.
如果你觉得走到今天实属不易
And if you think it was hard getting here,
你就能开始明白为了保住权位我会不惜一切
you're beginning to understand what I'm willing to do to stay.
我一眼望向拥挤的人群
I look across at this crowd gathered today
我很清楚他们不是我的支持者
and I know that these are not my supporters.
我看到的是一群脸上挂着微笑
I'm looking at people who are waiting,
等待着自己的机会来临的人
with a smile on their face, for their turn.
那些笑得最开怀
And the most vicious among them
鼓掌最热烈的人  也是其中最阴险的
are the ones who are smiling and clapping the hardest.
权力正如房地产  还记得吗
Power is a lot like real estate. Remember?
-愿上帝助我  -愿上帝助我
- So help me God. - So help me God.
美国人民  我听到了你们的声音
America, I hear you.
我听到了你们所有人的声音
I hear all your voices.
我听到了你们的挣扎  你们的担忧
I hear your struggles, your concerns,
但最重要的是  我听到了你们的希望
but most of all, I hear your hope.
每个人都希望得到机会和保障
Opportunity and security is what we all want.
所以在我上任后的百天之内  我会团结两党
And in my first 100 days, I will reach across party lines
让我的政府  也是你们的政府
and devote my administration, your government,
保障你们的需要
to securing them.
老年人以及他们所依赖的
For too long we have ignored
医疗保险已经被我们忽视了太久
our seniors and the healthcare they depend on.
所以我要致力于改善医保政策
That is why I am committed to fixing Medicare
取得成效前  我不会增加一毛钱预算
before I devote one more dime to the program.
《美就法》只是个开始
AmWorks was only the beginning.
我们得学会不再依赖福利津贴
We have to learn to live without entitlements,
因为我们不是不劳而获的民族
because we are not an entitled people.
我相信你们的每一滴汗水  每一分耕耘
I believe in your sweat. I believe in your hard work.
我今天要向大家承诺的  就是就业机会
And a job, that's what I'll promise you today.
你连一句话都不能给他吗
You couldn't give him one line?
对不忠诚的人我们一个子也不会给
We give no quarter to those that are disloyal.
今天传达的信息不是针对他一人
The message sent today wasn't just for him.
-报仇会燃起艾力克斯的斗志  -我也是
- Alex feeds off of retribution. - So do I.
-他值得你引战吗  -没有中间地带
- Is he worth the fight? - There is no neutrality.
我要求完全的忠诚  不然你就是我的敌人
I expect total loyalty or you are an enemy.
明白了  总统先生
Understood, Mr. President.
你怎么想
What are you thinking?
又称《America》  爱国歌曲
曾是默认的美国国歌
*让人民发出声音*
*Let mortal tongues awake*
BGM: My Country, 'Tis of Thee
*让人民畅快呼吸*
*Let all that breathe partake*
*让人民打破沉默*
*Let rocks their silent break*
我就是喜欢这些爱国的东西
I have a soft spot for that patriotic stuff.
请伸开手臂  岔开腿
Please spread your arms and legs.
什么
Excuse me?
否则  别想采访
Otherwise, there is no interview.
还有  请你脱掉外套
And if you would please take off your jacket.
-我是个记者  -我知道
- I'm a journalist. - I know.
我住在伦敦时读过你的报道
I read you when I was living in London.
-我不是间谍  -我知道
- So I'm not a spy. - I know you're not a spy.
现在还有人用那个词吗
Does anyone even use that word anymore?
采访不会在这里进行
So the interview won't be happening here.
-我们说好的  -我们得带你去另一个地方
- Uh, we agreed... - We need to move you to another location.
对不起  你不能用自己的人
Oh, and I'm sorry, you cannot use your own crew.
-这不可接受  -那采访就得推迟
- That's unacceptable. - Then the interview will have to wait.
我们不能信任你们的人
We cannot trust your people.
你也不想让麦卡伦先生有危险吧
And you wouldn't want to endanger Mr. Macallan, would you?
你来吗  鲍德温女士
Are you coming, Miss Baldwin?
你的手机得留下
And your cell phone needs to stay here.
谢谢
Thank you.
支持你的人很多
You have a lot of support out there,
不管总统说了  或没说什么
no matter what the president did or didn't say.
有很多人乐意跟你合作
There are people eager to work with you.
我该告诉你
I should tell you...
我要煽动共和党人
I'm encouraging the Republicans
重启宣战委员会
to restart the Declaration of War Committee,
调查总统
to investigate the president.
这很大胆
That's bold.
-我并不是想打动你  -很冒险
- I'm not trying to impress you with that. - It's risky.
你不想跟白宫的人为敌
You don't want an enemy in the White House.
但你现在在白宫了
But you're in the White House now.
你对我是什么
And you're what to me?
让我帮你吧
Why don't you let me help you?
不非得让其他人输你才能赢
Everybody doesn't have to lose for you to win, right?
肖恩·杰弗瑞斯在吗
Is Sean Jeffries there?
-谁找他  -你是谁
- Who's calling? - Who's this?
我为汤姆·汉默施密特工作
I work for Tom Hammerschmidt.
我不明白为什么把我转接给你
I don't understand why I was transferred to you.
接待员是我的朋友  我认识他  她认识他
The receptionist is a friend of mine. I know him. She knows him.
我已经联系他一天了
Well, I've been trying to reach him all day.
我可以替你捎话
I can take a message.
不用  我晚点再打吧
No, I'll try him later.
他已经不在这里工作了
Look, he doesn't work here anymore, so...
-我是他女朋友  -没事的
- I'm his girlfriend. - That's all right.
-你是谁  -算了
- Who is this? - Don't worry about it.
我是赛斯·格雷森  我有料给你
Hey, it's Seth Grayson. I've got something for you.
莉安·哈维  要被赶走了
LeAnn Harvey, she's being pushed out.
嗯  她出局了
Yeah, she's out.
到了现在  你是唯一
Yeah, well, you're the only one
还得从我这儿听来的人了
that's got me telling you at this point.
好吧  我正在写发布稿
Okay. I'm writing the release right now.
好  再见
All right, bye.
我是赛斯·格雷森
Hey, it's Seth Grayson.
我有料给你
Yeah, I got something for you.
凯特·鲍德温的人本来都准备好了
Kate Baldwin's people were ready to go,
但俄联邦安全局换掉了她的人
but the FSB replaced the crew.
你牙上有东西
You have something on your tooth.
我们知道他们要去哪吗
Do we know where they were going?
不  但他们还在受追踪
No, but they're still being tracked.
凯特·鲍德温就不该跟他说上话
Kate Baldwin was never supposed to talk to him.
-这采访绝不能进行  -我们还有时间
- This interview cannot happen. - We still have time.
不  没有了
No, we don't.
我们得介入
We need to go in.
这可能会产生难以预料的后果
And there might be some unforeseen consequences.
我觉得艾丹不会透露任何
I don't think Aidan would reveal anything
会伤害我  或其他人的信息
that would endanger me... or anyone else.
你跟他的交情有多久
How far back do you and he go?
很久
Far.
仅此而已
That's all.
很遗憾要如此结局
I'm sorry it has to end this way.
我不需要你的同情
I don't need your sympathy.
你快好了
You almost ready?
该死  我找不到我的F了
God damn it. I can't find my "F."
肯定是被人偷了
Someone must have stolen it.
肯定还会找到的
I'm sure it will turn up somewhere.
汤姆  你这身礼服真帅
Tom, you look very handsome in a tuxedo.
我装作撑得起礼服的人
I act like a man that can wear a tuxedo
我突然就撑得起礼服了
and suddenly I'm a man who can wear a tuxedo.
先用这个凑合吧
This should do for now.
-我刚看到艾瑞克·罗林斯来了  -是啊
- I just saw that Eric Rawlings arrived. - Yes.
汤姆  我们过会儿在楼下跟你碰头
Tom, we'll meet you downstairs in just a few minutes.
好
Sure.
斯坦普说  我们一小时后就能有
Stamper tells me that we'll have a bead on Macallan's location
麦卡伦下落的线索了
in about an hour or so.
我刚跟简·戴维斯说了话  她的联络人准备好了
I just spoke to Jane Davis. Her contacts are ready and waiting.
我们能撇清关系  弗兰西斯
We'll have distance, Francis.
我们会欠她的
We'll owe her.
你很帅  很有总统气质
You look very beautiful. Presidential.
你才美  有副总统的气质
You look beautiful. Vice Presidential.
就是这晚  佐伊被杀的那晚
Here we are. The night of Zoe's death.
你觉得那是谁
Who does that look like to you?
一个等列车的普通白人
Just another white guy waiting for the train.
看仔细点
Look closer.
我知道你觉得那是谁  但我不能确定
I know who you think it might be, but... I'm really not sure.
关上门
Yeah, shut that door.
杰拉德·福特的儿子以前会
Gerald Ford's son used
偷偷溜上这些楼梯  去屋顶
to sneak up these stairs to go to the roof,
跟朋友演奏齐柏林飞艇
play Led Zeppelin to his friends.
少年就是少年  不管他在哪
Teenagers are teenagers, doesn't matter where.
这是
And this...
维克多·佩特罗夫摁灭雪茄的地方
is where Viktor Petrov put out his cigar.
那人似乎很不好对付
That guy seems like a real piece of work.
相信我  他的确是
Oh, believe me, he is.
你也是
So are you.
这就未必了
No, I don't know about that.
-你干什么  -对不起
- What are you doing? - Oh, I'm sorry.
你为什么说对不起
And what are you sorry about?
我以为你想要一样  你并不想要的东西
I thought you wanted something that you don't.
你觉得我想要什么
So what is it that you think I wanted?
我们可以再上去  我真的...
We can go back up. I'm... I'm really s...
据说  人体最脆弱的部分
You know, they say the most vulnerable part of the human body...
是喉咙
is the throat...
你要想真正知道自己对某人的感觉
and that you never really know how you feel about somebody...
就需要那人掐着你的喉咙
until they have their hands around your throat.
告诉我
So tell me.
你现在什么感觉
How do you feel now?
恭喜  总统先生
Congratulations, Mr. President.
以免我忘了  莉安·哈维让我跟你打招呼
Before I forget, LeAnn Harvey wanted me to say hello.
她怎么样
How is she?
她要我告诉你
Well, she wanted me to tell you
她没事  她不会有事
that she's... she's all right. She's gonna be all right.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
她现在  请假了
She's, um, taking a leave of absence.
至少他们是这么说的
Well, that's what they're calling it,
但看来
but it... it seems that
她被赶出政府了
she's being pushed out of the administration.
是她告诉我你在这儿的
She's the one who told me you were here.
叫我来跟你谈谈
Suggested I talk to you.
莉安雇了你  是吧
LeAnn hired you, isn't that right?
家族朋友
Friend of the family?
对  我们这就开始采访了吗
Yeah, um, are we starting the interview now?
不不  我们就聊聊  但应该就好了
No, no. We're just talking. But we should be ready soon.
对不起  我能...
I'm sorry. Can I, uh...
我们开始前  我能单独待会儿吗
Can I just have a second before we start?
-可以  当然  -好
- I think so. Sure. Um... - Okay.
我去...喘口气
Yeah. I'm... I'm gonna need some air.
不  我就回来
No, I just... I just need a second, okay?
好啊  去喘气吧
Of course. Get some air.
好
Okay.
我想借你的手机
I want your phone.
我想借你的手机  拿着
I need your phone. Take this.
一通电话
One call.
就一通
One.
喂
Hello?
莉安  是我
LeAnn, it's me.
天呐  艾丹
My God, Aidan.
我知道你有麻烦了  我们这么办
I know you're in trouble. Here's the plan.
拿支笔  记下这号码
All right. Get a pen. Write down this number.
他是个律师  他可以帮你出国
He... he's a lawyer. He can get you out of the country.
等你到了俄罗斯  我就能保护你
Once you're in Russia, I can protect you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为什么
Why?
他们还有多久会找到我
How long do I have before they come and get me?
他们就在外面
They're right outside.
如果我跑呢
And if I run?
会有人受伤  你不会想那么做的
Uh, people will get hurt. You don't want to do that.
我喜欢德州
I like Texas.
或许是因为阳光或尘土
Maybe it's the sun or the dust,
但人们打招呼时都会眯着眼
but people kind of squint when they say hello.
我一直喜欢那样
I always liked that.
我就不该走的
I never should've left.
你一直对我很好
You've always been very good to me.
我喜欢你妈妈
I liked your mother.
我很喜欢她
I liked her a lot.
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
不必
Don't be.
二楼有个守卫是我们的人
There's a guard on the second floor working with us.
他会护送你去个角落  有出租车在等着你
He'll escort you to a corner where a cab will be waiting.
会有人给你开门
Someone will open the door. Just...
上车就行
get in.
你不想念德州吗
So you don't miss Texas?
不  我想
No, I do.
我想获得安宁
I'm trying to find some peace with this
而你在帮倒忙
and you're not helping.
-就再问几个问题  -我要搬走了
- Just a couple more questions. - I'm moving, you know.
-我得到了新工作  -巴恩斯先生
- I got a new job... - Mr. Barnes?
他们将你女儿的死判为意外
They ruled your daughter's death an accident.
我开始有所怀疑了
I am starting to doubt that.
-我们能不能再说一两遍  -知道吗
- Could we just go over one or two more... - You know what?
我不能再这么下去了
I just can't keep doing this.
别再给我打电话了
Stop calling me, please.
采访不会进行了
The interview will not be happening.
会有人护送你回酒店
Someone will escort you back to your hotel.
总统先生
Mr. President.
希望我没来得太晚
I hope I'm not too late to the party.
你正好赶上隆重登场
I'd say you were just in time to make your grand entrance.
这一切开始时  我可没想过
Well, when all this started, I don't think I imagined myself
今晚会跟你一起站在这里
standing here with you tonight.
-再次恭喜你  总统先生  -谢谢
- Congratulations, Mr. President. Again. - Oh, thank you.
我要等你吗
Um, should I wait for you?
不用  舞会上见
No, no. I'll see you inside the party.
那么  罗梅洛如何了
So... how's Romero?
罗梅洛想让共和党人
Well, Romero wants to get the Republicans
重启宣战委员会
to restart the Declaration of War Committee.
好一份就职大礼
What a lovely inauguration gift.
别说你感到意外
Don't tell me you're surprised.
我没有
I'm not.
里面见  去喝一杯吧
I'll see you inside. Get a drink.
你可真美
Well, don't you look stunning.
这一晚很漫长  弗兰克
It's been a long night, Frank.
我得回家了
I need to get home.
得了  赏个脸吧
Come on. Do me the honor.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
道格  打扮得真帅
Doug! Don't you look good.
谢谢您  副总统女士
Thank you, Madam Vice President.
你见到弗兰西斯了吗
Have you seen Francis?
好一会儿没见着了  女士
Not for a little while, no, ma'am.
大家在纷纷离开了
Well, the party's breaking up.
我想让他来跟人道别
I want him to say goodbye to people.
-好  女士  我去找他  -道格
- Yes, ma'am. I'll let him know. - Doug?
我有个问题问你  就一件小事
I have a question for you. Just a small thing.
-怎么了  -你怎么没去看砍头
- What is it? - Why weren't you at the beheading?
-什么  -詹姆斯·米勒被砍头那晚
- What? - The night James Miller was beheaded.
我们都在  我们四个
We were all there, the four of us.
弗兰西斯  汤姆  莉安和我
Francis, Tom, LeAnn and myself.
你怎么不在
Why not you?
你见到弗兰西斯  就说我找他
You see Francis, tell him I'm looking for him.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我以为你迷路了
I thought you got lost.
不  我就想歇歇
No. I just needed a break.
我们要去跟客人道别吗
Shall we bid our guests farewell?
不  今晚还早呢
No, the night is young.
看我找到了什么
Look what I found.
他们要重启委员会
They're restarting the committee.
我以为我们扼杀了那个委员会
I thought we killed that committee.
众议院什么都野火烧不尽
Nothing ever really dies in the House.
只不过关注的人越来越少
It just plays in front of a smaller and smaller audience.
-这事可不小  -我知道
- This is serious. - I know.
但我们还是好好享受舞会吧
But let's enjoy the rest of the party.
你是做什么的
What do you do here?
我为他们工作
I work for them.
总统让我确保你安全回家
The president asked me to make sure that you get home safely.
我给你安排了一辆车
I have a car for you.
我还想多待一会儿
I thought I'd stay a little while longer.
总统明天早上要早起
The president has an early morning tomorrow.
这边请
Right this way.
那个导游
The tour guide?
-什么  -是的
- What?  - Yes.
搞什么  我应该拿那个导游怎么办呢
WTF. What am I supposed to do about the tour guide?
还在媒体接待室  汤姆  不是吧
The press briefing room, Tom, really?
我以为没人会在意
I didn't think anyone would care.
那我是该留下她还是让她走人呢
Well, should I... keep her on or let her go?
她这样做是很不专业的
I mean, it was rather unprofessional on her part.
她很擅长她的工作
She's good at her job.
汤姆...
Tom...
不要对我妻子不忠
don't cheat on my wife.
巴恩斯先生
Mr. Barnes?
你想到别的地方喝杯咖啡吗
Do you want to get a coffee somewhere away from this?
我一直在想你说的话
I keep thinking about what you said.
我在她的东西中找到了这个
I found this with her things.
父亲节那天
It was Father's Day...
是我最后一次跟她通话
the last time I heard from her.
我们不是很亲近
We weren't close.
我很惊讶她会打电话给我
I was surprised she called.
我当然很开心  但是...
I mean, I was happy, of course, but...
我能留着这个吗
Can I hold on to this?
我不知道
I didn't know...
她有麻烦了
that she was in trouble.
当警察问我她是不是有自杀倾向的时候
When the police asked if i thought she was suicidal,
崭露头角的记者
在华盛顿特区惨遭地铁事故身亡
2013年
11月5日
我说  "可能吧"
I said, "Maybe."
我并不了解她
I didn't know her, really.
我也是
Neither did I.
我会调查这个的
I'll look into this.
好
Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
政治新闻网  《早安乔》上说了五分钟
Politico. Five minutes on Morning Joe.
发新闻稿真的有必要吗
Was a press release really necessary?
你要去休假
You're taking a leave.
新闻稿上说你要休假
The press release said that you were taking a leave
来考虑一下你的职业选择
to consider your career options.
得看上去像真的才行  你知道的
This has to look real. You know that.
如果他们要和我见面怎么办
What if they need to meet with me?
那他们就会和你见面
Then they'll meet with you.
我可以叫保安护送你出去
I could have security escort you out.
那么既然现在厄舍是特别顾问了
So since Usher is special advisor now,
那你又算什么呢
where does that leave you?
我说过了  如果有需要  他们会给打你的
Like I said, they'll call you if they need you.
我可以成为你的朋友的  知道吗
I can be a friend to you, you know.
不必这样的
It doesn't have to be like this.
我没有朋友
I don't have any friends.
我把他安排在了巴黎的约旦大使馆
I landed him at the Jordanian Embassy in Paris.
我们计划什么时候把他弄出来
When do we plan to get him out?
据我所知  现在还不知道
Well, as I understand it, you don't yet know
麦卡伦先生可能告诉了佩特罗夫总统些什么
what Mr. Macallan may have told President Petrov.
我要麦卡伦回来  越快越好
I want Macallan back here sooner rather than later.
这些事不发生在美国境内会更好些
It's better if these things don't happen on American soil.
是  但我决定了
Yes, but I make those decisions.
当然  总统先生
Of course, Mr. President.
请放心
And rest assured,
这件事是查不到你们身上的
neither of your fingerprints are anywhere near this.
我们怎么处理莉安
So what do we do about LeAnn?
她参与了选举舞弊  天呐
She's been involved in election fraud, for Christ's sake.
她犯了很多错
She's made a lot of mistakes.
是的  但很多人都犯过
Yes, but lots of people have.
话是那么说  但有些人就走到头了
Yes, but some people run their course.
如今真难知道能相信谁
It's hard to know who to trust these days.
可不是嘛
Isn't it?
美国联邦政府内阁包括副总统在内  目前共24名成员
其中负责国家安全的  如国务卿  国土安全部长  国防部长  被认为最重要
此外司法部长  财务部长也是比较重要的位置
而交通部长  农业部长  教育部长等  被认为是相对次要的职位
但因为现任总统特朗普在竞选时承诺
上任后将进行总值1万亿美元的基础建设投资
所以交通部长在现政府中地位较高
现任交通部长是华裔赵小兰  她丈夫麦康诺是参议院多数党领袖
许多媒体认为  特朗普任命赵小兰负责交通部
除了因她在小布什政府任职时  表现优异之外
也可能是希望在基建政策上获得麦康诺的支持
"医保改革"过去八年来一直是美国政治斗争的核心议题
奥巴马的新医保法案在2010年通过后
就一直遭右翼政客及共和党选民的反对
共和党也借此先后夺回了国会两院的控制权
特朗普竞选时  一再承诺上台后会推翻和替代原有的医保法案
但上任后  实际操作却困难重重  现在的替代法案能否通过尚无定数
同时  现有的医保制度在美国社会遇到了大麻烦
2009年推行法案时  奥巴马称法案通过后  保费会大幅降低
但法案施行后  不仅保费年年暴涨  而且由于医保公司亏损严重
在进入2017年后  美国一些地区的百姓已经无法购买"奥巴马医保"
所以替代方案也是势在必行了